<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on </title>
    <link>/categories/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-UK</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Steps and considerations to run a successful segmentation with K-means, Principal Components Analysis and Bootstrap Evaluation</title>
      <link>/2019/09/steps-and-considerations-to-run-a-successful-segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/steps-and-considerations-to-run-a-successful-segmentation/</guid>
      <description>Clustering is one of my favourite analytic methods: it resonates well with clients as I’ve found from my consulting experience, and is a relatively straightforward concept to explain non technical audiences.
Earlier this year I’ve used the popular K-Means clustering algorithm to segment customers based on their response to a series of marketing campaigns. For that post I’ve deliberately used a basic dataset to show that it is not only a relatively easy analysis to carry out but can also help unearthing interesting patterns of behaviour in your customer base even when using few customer attributes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling with Tidymodels and Parsnip - A Tidy Approach to a Classification Problem</title>
      <link>/2019/09/modelling-with-tidymodels-and-parsnip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/modelling-with-tidymodels-and-parsnip/</guid>
      <description>Recently I have completed the online course Business Analysis With R focused on applied data and business science with R, which introduced me to a couple of new modelling concepts and approaches. One that especially captured my attention is parsnip and its attempt to implement a unified modelling and analysis interface (similar to python’s scikit-learn) to seamlessly access several modelling platforms in R.
parsnip is the brainchild of RStudio’s Max Khun (of caret fame) and Davis Vaughan and forms part of tidymodels, a growing ensemble of tools to explore and iterate modelling tasks that shares a common philosophy (and a few libraries) with the tidyverse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A gentle Introduction to Customer Segmentation - Using K-Means Clustering to Understand Marketing Response</title>
      <link>/2019/05/a-gentle-introduction-to-customer-segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/a-gentle-introduction-to-customer-segmentation/</guid>
      <description>Market segmentation refers to the process of dividing a consumer market of existing and/or potential customers into groups (or segments) based on shared attributes, interests, and behaviours.
For this mini-project I will use the popular K-Means clustering algorithm to segment customers based on their response to a series of marketing campaigns. The basic concept is that consumers who share common traits would respond to marketing communication in a similar way so that companies can reach out for each group in a relevant and effective way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>